Guide to the Montana Power Company Predecessor Company records 1880-1947
Montana Historical Society
- Phoenix Utility Company
  - Financial Records
    - Flathead Hydro-Electric Development: cost analyses, 1930-1933 (Box-folder 177 / 2)
    - Flathead Hydro-Electric Development: cost analyses, 1936-1938 (Box-folder 178 / 1-2)
    - Flathead Hydro-Electric Development: local cash receipts, 1930-1933 (Box-folder 179 / 1)
    - Insurance policies, 1928-1931 (Box-folder 179 / 2)
    - Morony Development: cash book, 1929-1930 (Volume 373)
    - Morony Development: cost distribution, 1929 (Box-folder 179 / 3)
    - Morony Development: daily material receipts, 1929 (Box-folder 179 / 4)
    - Trial balances and statements of specific construction accounts, 1931 (Box-folder 179 / 5)
    - Warehouse stores quantity record, 1936-1937 (Box-folder 179 / 6)
    - Miscellaneous, 1929, undated (Box-folder 179 / 7)
  - Reports
    - Report on Bozeman town distribution, 1931 (Box-folder 179 / 8)
    - Report on Columbus Distribution Job 11, undated (Box-folder 179 / 9)
    - Report on Red Lodge Distribution Job 14, undated (Box-folder 179 / 10)
    - Field office procedure manual: Phoenix Engineering Company, New York, 1936 (Box-folder 179 / 11)
- Plains Light and Water Company
  - Financial Records
    - General ledger, 1931-1936 (Box-folder 180 / 1)
    - Journals, 1930-1936 (Volume 374- 375)
- Powell Power Company
  - Court Papers
    - Powell Power Company vs. Corporation Trust Company of Delaware final decree, 1905 (Box-folder 180 / 2)
  - Organizational Records
    - Record book (includes articles of incorporation, bylaws, minutes), 1902-1903 (Box-folder 180 / 3)
- The Power Company
  - Financial Records
    - Cash book, 1902-1905 (Volume 376)
    - General ledger, 1902-1905 (Volume 377)
    - Journal, 1902-1905 (Volume 378)
  - Organizational Records
    - Certificate of incorporation and amendment, 1898, 1904 (Box-folder 180 / 4)
    - Stock certificates, 1899-1903 (Box-folder 180 / 5)
- Rife Electric Company
  - Financial Records
    - General ledgers, 1915-1917 (Box-folder 180 / 6-8)
- Rocky Mountain Power Company
  - General Correspondence
    - Miscellaneous (re Flathead power project), 1922-1927 (Box-folder 181 / 1)
  - Financial Records
    - Cash books, 1920-1935 (Volume 379- 380)
    - Checkstub book, 1920-1929 (Box-folder 181 / 2)
    - Financial and operating reports, 1930-1938 (Volume 381- 382)
    - Financial record book (includes journal, ledger, and trial balances), 1920-1929 (Box-folder 181 / 3)
    - Flathead land account, 1937-1938 (Box-folder 181 / 4-6)
    - Flathead land account: Kerr Project, 1930-1936 (Box-folder 181 / 7)
    - General ledger, 1935-1938 (Volume 383)
    - Statements of expenditures: project 5 [Oversize Box], 1929-1938 (Oversizebox 20)
  - Legal Documents
    - Application to Federal Power Commission for Flathead Project (includes organizational material on company, etc.), 1922 (Box-folder 182 / 1-2)
    - Application to Federal Power Commission for Flathead Project maps [Oversize: see Archives Map Case], 1922 (Oversize-folder 5)
  - Organizational Records
    - Record books (includes articles of incorporation, bylaws, minutes, etc.), 1920-1921, 1937-1938 (Box-folder 182 / 3-4)
    - Dissolution papers [removed from record book], 1939 (Box-folder 182 / 5)
  - Miscellany
    - Water flow data on Flathead River, 1907-1921 (Box-folder 182 / 6)
- Silver Bow Electric Light Company / Silver Bow Electric Light and Power Company
  - Historical Material
    - Historical information file, 1891-1892 (Box-folder 183 / 1)
  - Financial Records
    - General ledger, 1891-1892 (Box-folder 183 / 2)
  - Organizational Records
    - Record book: Silver Bow Electric Light Company (includes articles of incorporation, bylaws, minutes, etc.) [Oversize Box], 1889-1892 (Oversizebox 20)
    - Record book: Silver Bow Electric Light and Power Company (includes articles of incorporation, bylaws, minutes, etc.), 1892 (Box-folder 183 / 3)
    - Stockholder transfer journal, 1889-1892 (Box-folder 183 / 4)
- Snake River Electric Light and Power Company
  - Organizational Records
    - Bylaws, 1916 (Box-folder 183 / 5)
- Spring Creek Electric and Power Company
  - Organizational Records
    - Record book (includes bylaws, minutes), 1909-1920 (Box-folder 183 / 6)
- T.S. Henderson and Company
  - Reports
    - "Engineer's report of Ward River Ditch and Ward's Cove land, Bitter Root Valley, Montana", by M.D. Kippen, circa 1909 (Box-folder 183 / 7)
- Thompson Falls Power Company
  - Historical Material
    - Historical information file (includes sale of company to Montana Power Company), 1913-1929 (Box-folder 184 / 1)
  - Financial Records
    - Camp ledger, 1915 (Box-folder 184 / 2)
    - Cash books, 1913-1929 (Volume 384- 387)
    - Cash book: development, 1913-1917 (Volume 388)
    - Construction ledger: #100-199 (plant accounts), 1913-1917 (Box-folder 184 / 3)
    - Construction ledger: #200-365 (dam accounts), 1914-1917 (Box-folder 184 / 4)
    - Construction ledger: #400-1201, 1913-1917 (Box-folder 184 / 5-6)
    - Contractor's estimates: S.E. Peel (includes detailed descriptions of activities) [removed from badly water-damaged volume], 1914-1915 (Box-folder 184 / 7)
    - General ledger, 1912-1914 (Box-folder 184 / 8)
    - General ledgers, 1913-1917 (Box-folder 185 / 1-4)
    - General ledgers, 1918-1921 (Box-folder 186 / 1-4)
    - General ledgers, 1922-1925 (Box-folder 187 / 1-4)
    - General ledgers, 1926-1929 (Box-folder 188 / 1-4)
    - Inventory, December 1916 (Box-folder 189 / 1)
    - Invoices: Three Forks Portland Cement Company, 1914-1916 (Box-folder 189 / 2-3)
    - Invoices: B-W, 1915-1916 (Box-folder 189 / 4)
    - Monthly financial reports, 1916-1917 (Box-folder 189 / 5)
    - Monthly reports of expenditures, 1916-1929 (Box-folder 189 / 6-8)
    - Operating reports, 1915-1916 (Box-folder 189 / 9-10)
    - Operating reports: 6-month summaries, 1914 (Box-folder 189 / 11)
    - Power consumer ledger, 1913-1928 (Box-folder 190 / 1)
    - Power usage invoice books (include power transmission, losses etc. for Chicago, Milwaukee and St. Paul Railway, Missoula Light and Water Company Idaho Transmission Company, et al.), 1923-1929 (Box-folder 190 / 2-3)
    - Trial balances, 1914-1928 (Volume 389- 391)
    - Voucher register, 1915-1920 (Volume 392)
  - Legal Documents
    - Contracts, 1915, 1923 (Box-folder 190 / 4)
    - Mortgages, 1921, 1929 (Box-folder 190 / 5)
    - Power contracts: Chicago, Milwaukee and St. Paul Railway Company, 1913-1921 (Box-folder 190 / 6)
    - Power contracts: F-T, 1913-1921 (Box-folder 190 / 7)
  - Organizational Records
    - Articles of incorporation, 1912 (Box-folder 190 / 8)
    - Minutes (includes sale of company to Montana Power Company), 1912, 1929 (Box-folder 190 / 9)
    - Stock certificates, 1912-1929 (Box-folder 190 / 10)
  - Subject File
    - Sale of Thompson Falls Power Company, Northwestern Development Company, and Idaho Water and Electric Power Company property to John D. Ryan, 1912-1913 (Box-folder 190 / 11)
- Thomson-Houston Electric Company
  - Interoffice Correspondence
    - Northwest Thomson-Houston Electric Company, 1892 (Box-folder 191 / 1)
- Union Electric Company
  - Historical Material
    - Historical information file (includes map of Dillon and photos), undated (Box-folder 191 / 2)
  - General Correspondence
    - Montana Electric Company, 1910-1913 (Box-folder 191 / 3)
    - Nolan and Donovan, attorneys, 1911 (Box-folder 191 / 4)
  - Financial Records
    - Cash book / voucher register, 1908 (Box-folder 191 / 5)
    - Customer ledger: A-Z, 1914-1935 (Box-folder 191 / 6)
    - General ledger, 1908-1913 (Box-folder 191 / 7)
    - General ledger, 1913-1933 (Box-folder 192 / 1-2)
    - Inventory book, 1921-1930 (Box-folder 192 / 3)
    - Inventory summary and analysis of expenditures (at time of dissolution), 1940 (Volume 393)
    - Journal / trial balance, 1908-1917 (Box-folder 192 / 4)
    - Journals / trial balances, 1917-1920, 1920-1939 (Volume 394- 395)
    - Meter and transformer book, 1915-1919 (Volume 396)
    - Operating reports, 1914-1918, 1931-1937 (Box-folder 192 / 5)
    - Summary of accounts, etc.: Lovell hydroelectric plant, Dillon, 1903-1920 (Box-folder 192 / 6)
    - Tax assessments, 1929 (Box-folder 192 / 7)
    - Voucher registers (includes Dillon Light and Power Company), 1905-1934 (Volume 397- 401)
    - Voucher register [Oversize Box], 1934-1940 (Oversizebox 20)
    - Working papers: Dillon distributing system valuation, 1931-1937 (Box-folder 192 / 8)
  - Legal Documents
    - Abstracts of title, 1911, 1923 (Box-folder 193 / 1-2)
    - Purchase of Union Electric Company and Beaverhead Transmission Company by Montana Power Company, 1939 (Box-folder 193 / 3)
    - Street lighting contract: City of Dillon, 1939 (Box-folder 193 / 4)
  - Organizational Records
    - Bylaws, 1908 (Box-folder 193 / 5)
    - Record book (includes articles of incorporation, minutes, annual reports, etc.), 1908-1940 (Box-folder 193 / 6-7)
    - Stock certificates, 1920-1938 (Box-folder 193 / 8)
    - Stockholder ledger and journal [some material transferred to separate folder], 1908-1939 (Box-folder 193 / 9-10)
  - Reports
    - "Estimate of present value of physical property of Union Electric Company and Beaverhead Transmission Company", August 1937 (Box-folder 193 / 11)
    - Public Service Commission report by R.J. Cobban, 1919 (Box-folder 193 / 12)
    - Public Service Commission report by Fred E. Buck, 1926-1927 (Box-folder 193 / 13)
    - "Report of the reproduction value of the Union Electric Company's property Dillon, Montana", by Fred W. Hassan, 1926 (Box-folder 193 / 14)
    - "Report on Dillon, Montana", by S.P. Hogan [several versions], 1938 (Box-folder 193 / 15)
    - "Report on present physical conditions and earning possibilities of the Union Electric Company, Dillon, Montana" by M. Hebgen, 1912 (Box-folder 193 / 16)
    - "Report on Union Electric Company, of Dillon, Montana" by H.R. Cochrane, 1919 (Box-folder 193 / 17)
  - Miscellany
    - Field book, circa 1930 (Box-folder 193 / 18)
    - Shutdown reports, 1936-1937 (Box-folder 193 / 19)
- United Missouri River Power Company
  - Historical Material
    - Historical information file, undated (Box-folder 194 / 1)
  - Court Papers
    - County of Lewis and Clark vs. United Missouri River Power Company complaint, 1911 (Box-folder 194 / 2)
    - United States Mortgage Company vs. United Missouri River Power Company; Central Trust Company of New York vs. United Missouri River Power Company foreclosure proceedings, 1910-1912 (Box-folder 194 / 3-5)
  - Financial Records
    - Cash book, 1906-1911 (Box-folder 195 / 1)
    - Cash book: Reorganization Committee, 1912 (Box-folder 195 / 2)
    - Claims account due to bursting of Hauser Lake Dam, April 14, 1908, 1908-1910 (Box-folder 195 / 3)
    - Customer journal: Boulder, 1910-1912 (Box-folder 195 / 4)
    - Customer journal: Radersburg, 1910-1912 (Box-folder 195 / 5)
    - Customer ledger: Boulder, 1910-1912 (Box-folder 195 / 6)
    - Financial statements: Helena, 1909-1910 (Box-folder 196 / 1-2)
    - Financial statements: overall corporate [Oversize Box], 1910 (Oversizebox 21)
    - General ledger, 1906-1909 (Box-folder 196 / 3)
    - General ledger, 1909-1911 (Box-folder 197 / 1)
    - General ledger, 1909-1911 (Volume 402)
    - General ledger: G.F. Shelton, receiver, 1911-1912 (Volume 403)
    - General ledger: Reorganization Committee, 1912 (Box-folder 197 / 2)
    - Journals, 1906-1911 (Box-folder 197 / 3-4)
    - Journal, 1909-1911 (Volume 404)
    - Journal, 1911 (Box-folder 198 / 1)
    - Journal: G.F. Shelton, receiver, 1911-1912 (Volume 405)
    - Trial balances, 1906-1907, 1911-1912 (Box-folder 198 / 2)
    - Trial balances (includes Helena Power Transmission Company, 1908; Missouri River Power Company, 1908; Capital City Power Company, 1908-1909), 1908-1910 (Volume 406)
    - Voucher registers, 1908-1911 (Volume 407- 409)
    - Voucher register index [Oversize Box], 1908-1911 (Oversizebox 21)
    - Voucher register and Hauser Lake account, 1909-1911 (Box-folder 198 / 3)
  - Legal Documents
    - Contracts: Anaconda Copper Mining Company and subsidiaries (as successor to Helena Power Transmission Company and Missouri River Power Company), 1910-1911 (Box-folder 198 / 4)
    - Freighting contract: Charles W. Palmer (re Hauser Lake Dam reconstruction), 1908 (Box-folder 198 / 5)
    - Merger agreement: Missouri River Power Company, Helena Power Transmission Company, United Missouri River Power Company, 1909 (Box-folder 198 / 6)
    - Mortgages, 1908-1911 (Box-folder 198 / 7)
    - Power contracts: A-W, 1909-1911 (Box-folder 198 / 8)
    - Reorganization agreement and plans, 1911-1912 (Box-folder 198 / 9)
  - Maps
    - Map of Canyon Ferry Dam, Hauser Dam, and proposed Wolf Creek Dam, undated (Box-folder 198 / 10)
  - Organizational Records
    - Bond certificate book, 1906 (Box-folder 198 / 11)
    - Minutes [typed transcript], June 1909 (Box-folder 199 / 1)
    - Minutes index book, 1908- (Box-folder 199 / 2)
    - Stock certificate (blank), undated (Box-folder 199 / 3)
    - Stockholder journals (common and preferred), 1906-1911 (Box-folder 199 / 4-6)
    - Stockholder ledger (common and preferred) [Oversize Box], 1906-1911 (Oversizebox 19)
    - Stockholder lists, 1906-1911 (Box-folder 199 / 7)
    - Stockholder transfer register, 1906-1910 (Box-folder 199 / 8)
    - Subscription receipts for notes, 1908-1910 (Box-folder 199 / 9)
  - Reports
    - Report to John D. Ryan on company properties, 1912 (Box-folder 200 / 1)
    - "Statement of controversy between United Missouri River Power Company and Anaconda Copper Mining Company", undated (Box-folder 200 / 2)
  - Miscellany
    - Lists of property and rights, 1896-1910 (Box-folder 200 / 3)
- Valier Townsite Company
  - Reports
    - Report by Public Service Commission engineer J.H. Bonner, 1921 (Box-folder 200 / 4)
- Valley Mercantile Company
  - Financial Records
    - Inventory, 1910 (Box-folder 200 / 5)
  - Legal Documents
    - Contract: City of Hamilton, 1910 (Box-folder 200 / 6)
  - Organizational Records
    - Minutes, August 1910 (Box-folder 200 / 7)
  - Miscellany
    - Water samples: Skalkaho Creek, Reservoir, Ravalli Hotel in Hamilton, 1910 (Box-folder 200 / 8)
- Western Lumber Company
  - General Correspondence
    - Miscellaneous (correspondents include Walter M. Bickford, Collins Land Company, Joseph M. Dixon, John M. Evans, Montana Industrial Accident Board, C.H. Richardson, A.H. Wethey), 1905-1919 (Box-folder 200 / 9)
  - Court Papers
    - John Doyle vs. Western Lumber Company (re injury), 1913-1914 (Box-folder 200 / 10)
    - Napoleon Gagnon vs. Western Lumber Company (re injury), 1925 (Box-folder 200 / 11)
    - Western Lumber Company vs. W.J. and W.F. Garrity (re money owed), 1914 (Box-folder 200 / 12)
    - Western Lumber Company vs. Missoula County (re taxes), 1922-1925 (Box-folder 200 / 13)
  - Financial Records
    - Tax assessment, 1922-1924 (Box-folder 200 / 14)
  - Legal Documents
    - Miscellaneous, 1894-1925 (Box-folder 200 / 15)
  - Organizational Records
    - Miscellaneous (includes minutes, list of stockholders, annual report, dissolution), 1904-1925 (Box-folder 200 / 16)
  - Miscellany
    - Transit notebook; levels and cross-sections, 1910-1913 (Box-folder 200 / 17)
- Western Montana Flouring Company
  - Interoffice Correspondence
    - Miscellaneous, 1903 (Box-folder 201 / 1)
  - Financial Records
    - Trial balance; milling report; etc., 1903 (Box-folder 201 / 2)
  - Organizational Records
    - Application for dissolution, 1917 (Box-folder 201 / 3)
    - Record book (includes minutes, articles of incorporation, annual statements, corporate taxes), 1901-1917 (Volume 410)
- Williams-Hill Company
  - Financial Records
    - Journal, 1916-1922 (Volume 411)
- Multi-Company Materials
  - Financial Records
    - Cash requirements (includes Helena Power Transmission Company; Great Falls Electric Properties; Butte Gas Light and Fuel Company; Butte Electric and Power Company; Phoenix Electric Company; Madison River Power Company; Billings and Eastern Montana Power Company; Montana Reservoir and Irrigation Company), 1909 (Box-folder 201 / 4)
    - Comparative monthly financial statements (includes Montana Power Company; Great Falls Power Company; Thompson Falls Power Company), 1916-1927 (Volume 412- 413)
  - Maps
    - Maps of transmission system (includes Madison River Power Company; Northwestern Development Company; Great Falls Power Company; Missouri River Power Company; Helena Power Transmission Company; Butte Electric and Power Company; et al.) [includes property descriptions] RESTRICTED: FRAGILE use only if property descriptions are needed [Oversize Box], 1905-1913 (Oversizebox 22)
    - Maps of transmission system (includes Madison River Power Company; Northwestern Development Company; Great Falls Power Company; Missouri River Power Company; Helena Power Transmission Company; Butte Electric and Power Company; et al.) [Oversize Box; photographic copies], 1905-1913 (Oversizebox 22)
  - Reports
    - Transmission line construction reports (state-wide), 1909-1916 (Box-folder 201 / 5)
- Walter M. Bickford
  - General Correspondence
    - American Power and Light Company, 1928 (Box-folder 202 / 1)
    - Anaconda Copper Mining Company (correspondents include John R. Toole, D. Gay Stivers, Kenneth Ross), 1911-1928 (Box-folder 202 / 2)
    - J.H. Anderson (New York) [see also William A. Clark Estate; William A. Clark's Office], 1922, 1927-1928 (Box-folder 202 / 3)
    - A (correspondents include C.M. Allen, Lolo; American Law Book Company; Anaconda Anglers' Club), 1911-1926 (Box-folder 202 / 4)
    - Ba-Be (correspondents include George T. Baggs, Anaconda; M.D. Baldwin, Kalispell; Barclay and Booth Abstract Company, Butte; Paul Bartless, New York; John S. Beall, Portland, Oregon; R.W. Beck, Hamilton; Robert F. Bell), 1911-1928 (Box-folder 202 / 5)
    - Bickford (includes Elizabeth, H.K., J.W., Katherine, Robert S., Susie M., nephew Walter, W.J.), 1911-1927 (Box-folder 202 / 6)
    - Big Creek Mining Company, Wallace, Idaho, 1912-1927 (Box-folder 202 / 7)
    - Charles A. Blackburn, 1911-1916 (Box-folder 202 / 8)
    - James M. Brown (re wartime Washington, D.C.), 1916-1918 (Box-folder 202 / 9)
    - Bi-Br (correspondents include John Bielenberg, Deer Lodge; F.L. Birdsall, International Falls, Minnesota; Blackfoot Land Company; Blackfoot Forest Protective Association; I.R. Blaisdell, Plains; I.D. Bogan, San Francisco; Bonita Club; A.J. Bower, Helena; Edward F. Brown, Burke, Idaho), 1911-1918 (Box-folder 202 / 10)
    - Butte Anglers Club (correspondents include D. Gay Stivers, William Lippincott, Arthur Perham), 1911-1917 (Box-folder 202 / 11)
    - Butte Electric Railway Company (correspondents include J.R. Wharton, E.J. Nash), 1911-1925 (Box-folder 202 / 12)
    - Bu-By (correspondents include E.C. Buckley, Boat Builder, Seattle, Washington; H.M. Buell, Helena; Massena Bullard, Helena; E.F. Bunker, Bozeman; H.J. Burleigh, Plains; Butte Electric and Power Company; J.F. Byrne, Ronan), 1911-1928 (Box-folder 202 / 13)
    - George H. Casey (Butte), 1911-1913 (Box-folder 202 / 14)
    - Chicago, Milwaukee and Puget Sound Railway; Chicago, Milwaukee and St. Paul Railway, 1911-1928 (Box-folder 202 / 15)
    - Ca-Ci (correspondents include B.A. Calkins, Butte; John L. Campbell, Helena), 1911-1928 (Box-folder 202 / 16)
    - Alice H. Clark, 1918 (Box-folder 202 / 17)
    - Amanda Clark (Mrs. Joseph K.), 1911 (Box-folder 202 / 18)
    - Charles W. Clark (Missoula; Jerome, Ariz.), 1911-1927 (Box-folder 202 / 19)
    - Charles W. Clark (telegrams re Senate fight, mostly in code), 1903 (Box-folder 202 / 20)
    - Ed Clark (Los Angeles), 1911-1913 (Box-folder 202 / 21)
    - J. Ross Clark, 1911-1927 (Box-folder 202 / 22)
    - Paul Clark Home (Butte; May White president), 1911-1912 (Box-folder 202 / 23)
    - William A. Clark (re Senate fight etc, includes letters to Clark from J.A. Largent and letters to Bickford from Allen Easterly), 1900-1911 (Box-folder 203 / 1)
    - William A. Clark (includes copies of some letters of Clark to others), 1908-1913 (Box-folder 203 / 2-14)
    - William A. Clark (includes Missoula labor controversy; founding of Missoula Businesmen's Association), 1914-1916 (Box-folder 204 / 1-10)
    - William A. Clark, 1917-1922 (Box-folder 205 / 1-15)
    - William A. Clark, 1923-1925 (Box-folder 206 / 1-4)
    - William A. Clark Estate (J.H. Anderson), 1925-1926 (Box-folder 206 / 5)
    - William A. Clark Jr., 1909-1928 (Box-folder 206 / 6-10)
    - William A. Clark III, 1925-1928 (Box-folder 206 / 11)
    - William A. Clark Jr. Library (Cora Sanders; Robert E. Cowan), 1928 (Box-folder 206 / 12)
    - William A. Clark's Office, Butte (Fred J. Furman), 1923-1924 (Box-folder 206 / 13)
    - William A. Clark's Office, Butte (W.D. Mangan), 1917-1926 (Box-folder 206 / 14)
    - William A. Clark's Office, Butte (H. McLeod), 1911-1913 (Box-folder 206 / 15)
    - William A. Clark's Office, Butte (J.C. Phillips), 1911-1927 (Box-folder 206 / 16)
    - William A. Clark's Office, Butte (W.C. Siderfin), 1911-1921 (Box-folder 206 / 17-18)
    - William A. Clark's Office, Butte (A.H. Wethey, general manager), 1908-1910 (Box-folder 206 / 19-20)
    - William A. Clark's Office, New York (J.H. Anderson; H.H. St.Clair), 1911-1921 (Box-folder 207 / 1)
    - W.A. Clark and Brother (Alex J. Johnston; J.K. Heslet), 1909-1927 (Box-folder 207 / 2-4)
    - Clark Legal Department (J.L. Templeman; Fred Furman; Jessie Roscow), 1921-1928 (Box-folder 207 / 5-8)
    - Clark-Missoula Power Company (S.R. Inch), 1911-1912 (Box-folder 207 / 9)
    - Clark-Montana Realty Company (W.C. Siderfin; Fred Furman; W.F. Klatt; J.C. Phillips), 1925-1928 (Box-folder 207 / 10)
    - Cl (correspondents include C.N. Clark; Will Clark; J.E. Clifford, deputy state game warden), 1912-1919 (Box-folder 207 / 11)
    - Jeremiah Collins / Collins Land Company (re lieu land selections Western Lumber Company; Santa Fe Railroad scrip) [see also subject file "Forest lieu land selections"], 1911-1928 (Box-folder 207 / 12-14)
    - Consaul and Heltman (re Western Lumber Company), 1913, 1918 (Box-folder 208 / 1)
    - Co-Cy (correspondents include R.M. Cobban Realty Company; Sid J. Coffee, Missoula; John E. Corette; Stephen P. Cushman, Boston), 1909-1928 (Box-folder 208 / 2)
    - Davis-Daly Copper Company (includes quarterly reports), 1916-1918 (Box-folder 208 / 3)
    - Democratic State Central Committee (J.L. Dobell), 1912, 1925 (Box-folder 208 / 4)
    - W.A. Diltz; Mrs. W.A. Diltz (Fish Lake Mountain Fish Hatchery), 1928-1929 (Box-folder 208 / 5)
    - Joseph Dingle Boat Works, 1917-1928 (Box-folder 208 / 6)
    - Joseph M. Dixon, 1910-1913 (Box-folder 208 / 7)
    - D (correspondents include H.J. Daigle, Bonita; Deer Lodge County; Charles L. Dering, Chicago; J.L. Dobell, Butte; Michael Donlan, Butte; C.P. Drennen, Butte; Cornelius H. Duggan, Fernie, B.C.), 1909-1928 (Box-folder 208 / 8)
    - Elks Club, Missoula, 1911-1913 (Box-folder 208 / 9)
    - John M. Evans, Congressman, 1908-1928 (Box-folder 208 / 10-11)
    - Exchange National Bank, Spokane, Washington (C.E. McBroom, re organization of Missoula Street Railway Company), 1909-1917 (Box-folder 208 / 12)
    - E (correspondents include Henry J. Elliott, Montreal, Canada; Ed G. Ellis, Sierra Madre, California; M.J. Elrod, Missoula; Erie Railroad Company; L.O. Evans, Butte), 1912-1927 (Box-folder 209 / 1)
    - First National Bank [various towns], 1909-1927 (Box-folder 209 / 2)
    - Fisher, Wilson, Battram, and Hamilton (Winnipeg, Canada), 1911 (Box-folder 209 / 3)
    - Adella M. Fowle (re Bickford and Mansur genealogy), 1911 (Box-folder 209 / 4)
    - C.M. Fowler (re Montana Mutual Dairy Loan Association; wife's illness), 1925 (Box-folder 209 / 5)